Daniel Sukoneck

resume.sukoneck.com daniel@sukoneck.com

I am a creative cloud and infrastructure practitioner whose passion for DevOps, SRE, and improving user experiences rivals my passion for team building, culture, and leadership. I have had great opportunities to lead large, constrained, and impactful projects with diverse teams to meet some of the most discerning business needs.

Experience

DevOps Engineer, Grand Canyon Education, 2019 - Present

Automation and platform development for a leading higher education managed services provider.

Senior Cloud and Infrastructure Consultant, West Monroe Partners, 2014 - 2019

As a senior consultant at a mid-size business and technical consulting firm, I was responsible for executing technical and strategic infrastructure focused consulting engagements and promoting the growth and mentorship of my team.

- Awarded the west coast offices' Consultant of the Year and selected for a mentorship program with executive leadership
- Helped a leading financial institution develop and execute their cloud strategy by creating a two-year migration roadmap with partnership from IT and business leadership. Satisfied security, audit, and risk requirements by implementing custom migration pipeline and five-epic scrum template. Developed future-state architecture and business continuity designs for more than 50 applications. Led as many as 15 concurrent application teams, each with up to 10 dedicated consulting and client resources, to migrate applications from on-premises data centers to a hybrid of Azure regions and colocations. Culminated in leading more than 60 resources through the migration of 15 core banking applications in a single weekend with no critical incidents
- Salvaged a behind-schedule data center migration for a healthcare analytics company by finishing all requirements gathering, design, and implementation within four weeks. Built and installed all infrastructure in the new colocation including VMware cluster, Dell storage array, and Cisco switch stack. Designed network segmentation for future-state systems. Planned and led production cutover to new systems. Concurrently, separated all user systems from parent company by executing Active Directory, network, DNS, VPN, and VOIP migrations while also hiring and training a Sysadmin
- Formal mentor of five junior resources with a focus on career progression, technical development, and professional growth. Conducted more than twenty formal reviews and provided continuous feedback to project team members
- Informed cloud strategies for over 50 applications and 5 clients by developing a custom analysis tool to determine the appropriate hosting model for an application given its architectural, risk, and cost factors, then rank the results to report risk and reward
- Provided actionable recommendations to improve the security posture of a leading healthcare insurer by evaluating 12 information security tools on their inherent effectiveness and current implementations
- Expanded team capabilities by spearheading proof of concepts for container orchestrators like Docker Swarm and for server migration tools such as Zerto and Azure Site Recovery. Helped design and build a physical lab environment with connectivity to networks in Azure and AWS

Network and System Administrator, Safety Services Company, 2013 - 2014

The primary sysadmin for the nation's largest provider of safety training materials. Its outbound sales centers span an enterprise of two main offices and five satellite locations with 500+ users in an Inc. 5000 fastest growing business environment.

- Trained and led a team of three desktop support technicians with a high end-user to technician ratio
- Managed NOC hardware relocation and data center rack reconstruction to improve disaster recovery
- Implemented VMware ESXi with vCenter and expanded SAN storage to accommodate growth while cutting costs
- · Administered Active Directory, Exchange, Dynamics, SharePoint, Lync, and user provisioning in a multiple domain network
- · Implemented and documented standard operating procedures for all desktop support issues including escalation
- Orchestrated enterprise reimage of desktops to standardize and ease administration
- Instigated and managed rollout of roaming profiles for mobile users

Certifications

- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate Terraform
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure MCSE
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate: Windows Server 2012 MCSA
- Cisco Certified Network Associate CCNA

Education

Arizona State University, Graduated 2012

- Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy
- Certificate, Ethics
- Certificate, Symbolic Systems